https://www.columbiabasin.edu/public-info/privacy-policy/

Introduction
Thank you for visiting our website and reviewing this Online Privacy Statement. This
Privacy Statement explains what we do with data collected as a result of your visit
to this website. It also describes several state and federal laws that apply to personally
identifiable information that you might provide in the course of navigating this site.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Data Collection and Use
Information collected if you only browse this siteWhen you browse this website, we may gather and store certain information about your
visit. We automatically collect and store the following information about your visit:1. The Internet domain and network address you use to access our site;2. The type of web browser and operating system you are using;3. The date and time of your visit;4. The pages you visit on this website; 5. The last website you visited before coming to ours; and 6. Other web traffic statistics such as Google Analytics or Piwik Analytics.
The information we automatically collect is saved and used by the College to improve
the content of our web services and to help us understand how people are using our
services. Information collected if you volunteer informationIf during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send us an email,
or perform some other transaction online, the following additional information may
be collected:
1. Your email address and contents of the email.2. Information volunteered in response to a survey.3. Information volunteered through an online form for any other purpose.
The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio,
video, and graphic information formats you send us. We will not usually ask for or
collect this kind of information from the general public through this website.Emails you send to us may be used to respond to issues and to further improve our
services. We may forward your email to another agency or a vendor for appropriate
action. The records retention schedules published by the State Archives require us to keep this information only so long as it is useful, and then destroy
it; these schedules change from time to time.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
User Tracking and Customization of Pages
To better serve our users, we use a variety of indicators to customize your browsing
experience with this website, including “cookies.” If you use your browser settings
to opt to block all cookies in the settings to your web browser (such as Internet
Explorer, Safari, Chrome or Firefox), (including essential cookies) this could affect
the availability and functionality of this website. We only have control over indicators
we provide and not over third party tools or other technologies deployed on this website
that may be created by using embedded third party applications.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Personal Information
Personally identifiable information (“PII”) means information about a natural person
that is readily identifiable to that specific individual. Personal information includes
such things as your name, address and phone number.We will not collect PII about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending
us email, or completing an online form or survey. You may choose not to contact us
by email or to provide any PII using an online form or survey. Your choice to not
participate in these activities will not restrict or impair your ability to use our
site and read or download any information provided on the site. If you choose to provide
PII by emailing us, participating in a survey, or completing an online form, we may
store this information. The Children's Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) governs online information gathering from or about children under the age of 13.
We are especially concerned about protecting children's privacy and do not knowingly
collect personal information from children or minors as defined by COPPA on our website.
Under COPPA, parental consent is required to collect, use or disclose personally identifiable
information about a child under the age of 13.If you have questions about how we use your personally identifiable information, you
can contact the College as shown in the Contact Information section of this statement.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Public Access to Information
Columbia Basin College is an agency of the State of Washington, therefore, our records
are governed by federal and state laws, including but not limited to the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 (FERPA); 20 U.S.C. § 1232g; 34 CFR Part 99; and Washington’s Public Records Act (RCW 42.56). Information you send to us may become a public record, and may be subject to public
inspection and copying if not otherwise protected from disclosure by federal or state
law. Please see Access to Public Records for further information on Public Records.
In the event of a conflict between this On-line Privacy Statement and the Public Records
Act or other law governing the College’s disclosure of records, the Public Records
Act or other applicable law will control.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Rights Regarding Your Data
You may have additional rights under applicable laws to request access to, erasure,
correction or transfer of your data. For example, State law requires agencies that
collect personally identifiable information to provide “procedures for correcting
inaccurate information, including establishing mechanisms for individuals to review
information about them and recommend changes in information they believe to be inaccurate.”
(RCW 43.105.365).The European Union’s General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) provides certain
rights to persons who were/are residing in the European Union when their data were/are
collected to request access to, correct, erase, or transfer their data. To the extent allowed by law, you may also withdraw consent you have given to certain
data processing, without penalty. Your withdrawal will not affect the legality of
the processing of your data up to the date on which you withdraw your consent. You can access any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using
the information in the Contact Information section of this page. We will do our best
to correct factual errors in your personally identifiable information if you send
us a written request that clearly shows the error. We will take reasonable steps to
verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Security
The College has taken steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized
access to information maintained by us. These measures are designed and intended to
prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and
information, and to provide reasonable protection of information in our possession.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Copyright
This site contains text, artwork, photos or other content that is copyrighted by others
and is being used with permission of the copyright holder. Therefore, we recommend
that you contact our Webmaster for permission to use any content contained on this site.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Disclaimer
The State of Washington, Columbia Basin College, its officers, and employees neither
warrant the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this
system, nor endorse any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this
system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy,
reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be
incorrect or not current. Any person or entity who relies on any information obtained
from this system does so at their own risk.Our website contains links to other websites. These include links to websites operated
by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses, including
but not limited to the websites of our vendors. When you follow a link to another
site, you are no longer on our website and this On-line Privacy Statement will not
apply-- you will be subject to the privacy terms of that new site.Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services,
or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name is for the information and convenience
of the public and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by
the State of Washington, Columbia Basin College, or its officers, employees or agents.We reserve the right to revise and update this Online Privacy Statement at any time
without notice by posting the revision on our site.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
Glossary
A network address is assigned to your computer or mobile device whenever you are using the Internet.
Network addresses can be IP address like this: 192.168.0.11 or like this: fc00:0:0:0:0:0:0:0:/7
or Ethernet addresses like this 00:00:00:FF:EE:11.Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in your device memory when you
visit a website. Cookies and similar technologies are widely used by websites to make
them work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the website operator
about how users are using their website. Most browsers allow you to block cookies
by adjusting the “settings,” “preferences” or “internet options.” To find out more
about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been set and how to manage and
delete them, please refer to your browser ‘help’ section, visit the Federal Trade Commission’s explanation on its website, or the Washington State privacy resources website.
Home
Online Privacy Policy
Columbia Basin College Online Privacy Policy
If you have questions about how we use your personally identifiable information, you
can contact the College by using the information in the Contact section at the bottom
of this page.Last updated July 2019.
Email:administration@columbiabasin.edu
Phone:509-547-0511
Address:2600 N. 20th Ave., Pasco, WA 99301
©
